Gary Roumanis

Technical Lead / Manager

Greater Seattle (425) 615-0163 groumanis@gmail.com

www.garyroumanis.com https://github.com/grouma https://www.linkedin.com/in/garyroumanis/



ABOUT

I'm a perpetual learner and passionate engineer with an eye for detail. I have a wide variety of experience from distributed systems to build tools. I've held diverse roles that required individual contribution, technical leadership, and people management. My primary focus throughout my career has been on developer productivity.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Google, Seattle - Software Engineer / Manager

APRIL 2015 - PRESENT

I'm currently the technical lead and manager of AngularDart which powers many of Google's largest enterprise web applications. Previously I was working on the Dart language team helping to build infrastructure and tools specifically geared towards web development. Core technologies include AngularDart, Flutter, JavaScript, Bazel, and of course Dart.

Microsoft, Seattle - Software Development Engineer

DECEMBER 2013 - MARCH 2015

I helped develop a near real-time, streaming, log processing service along with corresponding monitoring tools and dashboards. Core technologies included C#, Kafka, Zookeeper, Ember and Typescript.

Microsoft, Seattle - Program Manager

OCTOBER 2012 - DECEMBER 2013

I defined and managed the scope of various projects, such as Product Listings and Ads in Window's Search Charm. I specified requirements, conducted usability studies, triaged issues and assigned them to engineering teams.

McGill, Montreal - Research Assistant

APRIL 2012 - SEPT 2012

The *Irslib* library is a reverse search algorithm for vertex enumeration and convex hull problems. I adapted the synchronous *Irslib* library to take advantage of multiple processors and cores. The application was developed in C++ and made use of the free boost library. The source code is available here. Results from this research were <u>published</u> in Combinatorial Optimization and Applications.

Microsoft, Seattle - Program Manager Intern

APRIL 2011 - AUGUST 2011

I wrote functional specifications for multiple projects including a prototype which allowed for the display of various coupon advertisements within the paid search workflow of Bing. I also participated in the intern app competition and won the runner up prize. The app provided an internet streaming radio service, offering a simple way for people to share and discover music and playlists. The app had over 50,000 downloads with a 4.5 star rating.

McGill, Montreal - NSERC Undergraduate Student Research

APRIL 2010 - SEPTEMBER 2010

I helped design a framework for harnessing the computing power of humans to solve Multiple Sequence Alignment problems. The application front-end was developed in Flash ActionScript 3 while the back-end used Java and MySql. The application is maintained <a href="https://example.com/here/back-end/bac

EDUCATION

McGill University, Montreal - Joint honours in Computer Science and Mathematics SEPTEMBER 2008 - APRIL 2012

Bachelor of Science.

References

Available upon request.